asq.org 2014-06-30

# Privacy Policy - ASQ

The American Society For Quality, Inc. (ASQ), the owner of www.asq.org is strongly committed to protecting the privacy of its members, customers and visitors. This privacy policy describes what information ASQ will collect from visitors and purchasers such as yourself, and how we will use that information once it’s collected. This policy does not apply to the practices of any third party, affiliate, or business partner that ASQ does not own or control. 

This privacy policy applies to ASQ's Web site, www.asq.org. It does not apply to Web sites of any ASQ member, affiliate, Section, Division, or chapter. It does not apply to Web sites operated by organizations or groups who associate themselves in any way with ASQ. It does not apply to any other Web sites, including those that link to the ASQ Web site. Exclusivo México: consulta nuestro Aviso de Privacidad en [www.asq.com.mx](http://www.asq.com.mx/).

## Collection of non-personal data

If you browse ASQ's Web site and you are not an ASQ member, you do so anonymously. We only collect your e-mail address and other personal information when you provide it of your own free will. We log your IP address (the Internet address of your computer) to tell us which parts of our Web site you visit and how long you spend there. We do not link your IP address to anything personally identifiable. We also track what country you are accessing the Internet from, and what time and date you visited. 

The only other information automatically provided to us is the type of computer, operating system and Web browser you are using. Your browser supplies us with this information. We use this information from our server logs and analytics system to learn more about our visitors as a group, not about you as an individual. The information helps us identify overall usage patterns and trends on the site.

If you are an ASQ member and log in, we collect your first and last name, your membership type, your industry/market, which Forums/Divisions you are a member of and which publications you receive. We do this by placing a small bit of data called a “cookie” on your computer (see more about cookies below). Collecting this information helps us direct you to the information on our Web site that’s meant for you. 

## Collection of your personal information

Online forms are available for customers to request information, download articles, or purchase products and services. We obtain information you provide to us via these forms, as well as surveys and contests, such as your name, mailing address and e-mail address. We may use this information to provide you with information about the products and services offered by ASQ. In addition, this site uses registration forms for customers to register for courses, conferences, and/or certification exams. We collect information about you only if you voluntarily provide contact information within these forms. 

## Control of your personal information

ASQ will not sell or share your e-mail address with other organizations. However, other information you share may be used to provide you with information from ASQ or selected organizations about products, services or activities that may be of interest to you.

We occasionally hire other companies to provide limited services on our behalf, including electronic newsletter delivery and the processing of event registrations. We will only provide those companies with the information they need to deliver the service. They are prohibited from using that information for any other purpose. 

If you supply your personal information to an ASQ partner, such as a training provider or the Career Center, please be aware that ASQ no longer has control over the use of your personal information. We will not knowingly partner with companies that abuse personal information. However, be aware that our partner companies may contact you if you choose to conduct business with them. 

## Disclosure of your personal information

ASQ may disclose your personal information if required to do so by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) satisfy a legal order or comply with legal process; (b) defend the rights of ASQ or its affiliates or business partners; or (c) protect the personal safety of ASQ employees, agents, affiliates, business partners, customers or Web site users. 

## Access to your personal information

If you are an ASQ member, you can review and edit your personal information in the "My ASQ" area. Log in and click on "Manage My Account." 

Within “My ASQ” you can: 

  * View and edit the personal information you already have shared with ASQ. 
  * Change your e-mail address. 
  * Change your e-mail subscription preferences. 
  * Change your member password. 

Some services offered on www.asq.org collect information that is not accessible via “My ASQ.” In such cases, you can access and change your personal information by contacting ASQ.

## Cookies

A cookie is a tiny piece of information that a Web site stores on your computer during your visit. The next time you visit the Web site, your browser sends this bit of information back to the site. Cookies allow Web sites to maintain information on a particular user. For example, an online bookstore might use a cookie to identify you so it can store the contents of your shopping cart. You can configure most Web browsers to notify you when cookies arrive and can either ask your approval to accept them, or be set to refuse cookies outright. Most browsers also let you delete cookies you may have accepted in the past.

ASQ uses cookies to help guide members through our Web site (as described above) and to keep track of your shopping carts. A unique ID is assigned to each shopping session. Our Web server sends the shopping cart ID to your computer. If your browser is configured to accept cookies, the unique ID is stored on your computer and sent back to our Web server. This unique ID is retrieved and used by the server to keep track of the contents of your shopping cart, which is stored on our server. The ASQ Web site cookie will not damage your system or files in any way.

ASQ occasionally uses cookies to display ads on sites across the Internet. ASQ and third-party vendors, including Google, use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookies) and third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) together to report how your ad impressions, other uses of ad services, and interactions with these ad impressions and ad services are related to visits to ASQ.org. Any information that these third parties collect via cookies is not linked to any personal information collected by us.  To manage your ad settings visit: <https://www.google.com/settings/ads>. 

## Your credit card information

The American Society For Quality, Inc. is strongly committed to protecting the privacy of its members, customers and visitors. We collect credit card information, such as your card number and card expiration date, when you purchase products on our site. This site has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. We use a secure server to transmit sensitive data to and from our site. All data (including your credit card information) transmitted through our secure Web server is encrypted so no one else can read it. We will not voluntarily disclose your credit card information without your consent.

## Security

This site has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control.  We use a secure server to transmit sensitive data to and from our site. All data (including your credit card information) transmitted through our secure Web server is encrypted so no one else can read it. 

## Use of e-mail forwarding tools

If you send an e-mail via our Web site using the services called "e-mail this to a friend" or "forward this conversation to a friend," we do not use the e-mail address for any purpose other than to send your e-mail. We do not rent or sell these e-mail addresses. We generally discard the e-mail addresses some time after they have been used to send your e-mail.  You do not have permission to use these e-mail services to send spam. 

## ASQ privacy policy changes

If we decide to change our privacy policy for www.asq.org, we will post the modifications so that you will always know what information we gather, how we might use that information, and whether we will disclose it to anyone.
